Autograph File, B: Guide.
Autograph File, B,
- Bissell, William Henry, 1811-1860. Printed document, s.; Springfield, Ill., 15 Apr 1858., 1s.(1p.)
- Bissell, William Henry, 1811-1860. Printed document, s.; Springfield, Ill., 4 Nov 1859., 1s.(1p.)
- Bissy, Claude de Thiard, comte de, 1721-1810. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 5 Oct 1750., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (39). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bjornson, Bjornstjerne, 1832-1910. A.L.s.to [ ]; Rome, 18 Dec 1874., 1s.(1p.)
- Black, Adam, 1784-1874. A.L.s.to Captain Francis Frome; Aberdeen, 29 Jul 1837., 1s.(4p.)
  Gift of Mrs B.O. Peirce, 1936.
- Black, Frank Swett, 1853-1913. Printed document, s., Albany, 4 Nov 1898., 1s.(1p.)
- Black, John Charles, 1839-1915. 2 letters to Adam Badeau:
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 19 Dec 1887., 1s.(1p.)
  - MS.L.s.; Same, 28 Feb 1888., 1s.(1p.)
- Black, William, 1841-1898. A.L.s.to Annie (Adams) Fields; Brighton, 16 Mar [ ]., 1s.(2p.)
  Recat. fr. *5.1F.
- Black, William, 1841-1898. A.L.s.to [Miss ] Cochran; [London?] [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  No source, 4 June 1936.
- Black, William, 1841-1898. A.L.s. to James Thomas Fields; New York, 18 Oct 1876., 1s.(1p.)
  *50M-409. Transferred from the Boston Medical Library, 11 Apr 1951.
- Black, William, 1841-1898. A.L.s.to Laurence Hutton; Brighton, 24 Nov [ ]., 1s.(2p.)
- Blackburn, Henry, 1830-1897. A.L.s. to Jacob Klein; [London] 4 Jul 1888., 1s.(1p.)
  Concerning Randolph Caldecott.
  Gift of A. H. Parker, 1930.
- Blackburne, Francis, 1705-1787. 2 A.L.s.to Andrew Eliot:
  - Richmond, 23 Jan 1767., (1); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 18 Aug 1767., (2); 1s.(4p.)
    Concerning English political affairs.
- Blackfield, Edwin Howland. A.L.s.to Robert Keith Mackeye; [New York] 13 Jan 1903., 1s.(1p.)
- Blackfield, Edwin Howland. A.L.s.to Allan Marquand; New York, 22 Nov 1898., 1s.(2p.)
- Blackford, Daniel C. A.L.s.to Timley Brothers; [London] [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Blackford, Hattie. A.L.s.to [ ] Timley; Paris, 25 Apr 1845., 1s.(2p.)
- Blackie, John Stuart, 1809-1895. A.L.s. to [ Mills?]; Edinburgh, 25 Mar 1888., 1s.(3p.)
- Blackled, John C. A.promissory note s.; to John Knight; Marblehead, 6 Feb 1816., 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of R.T. Jackson, 9 Apr 1907.
- Blackmore, Richard Doddridge, 1825-1900. A.L.s. to [Abby Langdon] Alger; Teddington, 17 May 1888., 1s.(3p.)
  Gift of G.L. Kittredge, n.d.
- [Blackmore, Richard Doddridge, 1825-1900] 8 Envelopes, addressed in Blackmore's autograph to Elbridge Henry Goss; [various places] 1894-1897.
  The present location of the letters contained in these envelopes is unknown.
- Blackmore, Richard Doddridge, 1825-1900. A.L.s. to Mr., Mrs. or Miss Woggs Stevenson [i.e., Robert Louis Stevenson's dog]; [n.p., 1881?], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-155. Purchased with the Morris Gray fund from Austin Strong, 15 Oct 1942.
- Blackwell, Antoinette (Brown) 1825-1921. A.L.s.to Ben. W. Austin; Elizabeth, N.J., 19 Dec 1883., 1s.(1p.)
- Blackwell, Antoinette (Brown) 1825-1921. A.L.s.to Editors, Putnams Monthly; [New York] 27 Oct 1856., 1s.(1p.)
- Blackwell, Elizabeth, 1821-1910. A.L.s.(facsimile) to [ ]; New York,1856., 1s.(2p.)
  Circular letter, announcing that Elizabeth Blackwell is beginning practice in New York.
  *44M-64. Presented by Walter Stone Poor, Esq., 12 July 1944.
- Blackwell, Henry Brown,1825-1909. 4 A.L.s.to [Erastus Brainerd]:
  - Philadelphia, 29 Oct 1887., 1s.(1p.)
  - Boston, 21 Mar 1905., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 20 May 1905., 1s.(1p.)
  - Seattle, 11 Jul 1909., 1s.(1p.)
- Blackwood, William, 1836-1912. A.L.s.to [ ]; Edinburg, 15 Mar 1869., 1s.(4p.).
- Blagden, George Washington, 1802-1884. Letters to William Buell Sprague:
  - Saratoga, 24 Aug 1848., (1); 1s.(3p.)
  - Boston, 22 Sep 1848., (2); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 19 May 1849., (3); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 6 Aug 1849., (4); 1s.(3p.)
  - Nahant, 21 Aug 1849., (5); 1s.(2p.)
  - Saratoga, 24 Aug 1849., (6); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 28 Aug 1849., (7); 1s.(2p.)
  - Boston, 2 Sep 1850., (8); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 20 Sep 1850., (9); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 2 Apr 1851., (10); 1s.(4p.)
  - Boston, 2 May 1851., (11); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 12 Jul 1851., (12); 1s.(3p.)
  - Troy, 9 Sep 1852., (13); 1s.(1p.)
  - Boston, 15 Jun 1853., (14); 1s.(3p.)
  - Boston, 7 Aug 1854., (15); 1s.(2p.)
  - Washington, 4 Sep 1854., (16); 1s.(2p.)
  - Boston, 7 Dec 1854., (17); 1s.(2p.)
  - Boston, 22 Jun 1857., (18); 1s.(2p.)
  - Same, 29 Jun 1857., (19); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 13 Sep 1857., (20); 1s.(3p.)
  - Boston, 6 Sep 1864., (21); 1s.(3p.)
  - Catskill, 11 Jul 1865., (22); 1s.(3p.)
- Blaine, Harriet Bailey (Stanwood), 1828-1903. A.L.s.to [ ] Thatcher; Washington, 10 Feb 1893., 1s.(2p.)
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. Engraved passport, filled out in MS. and s. for William Croswell Doane; Washington, 3 Jan 1891., 1s.(1p.)
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. 3 autographs.
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. 2 A.L.s.to Adam Badeau:
  - Washington, 10 Jul 1870., 1s.(2p.)
  - Augusta, Me., 5 Aug 1871., 1s.(3p.)
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. A.L.s.to Constance [ ]; Bar Harbor, 12 [Jun 1892], 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of Mrs. C.C. Williams, 12 Sept 1940.
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. A.L.s.to Jacob Hart Ela; Washington, 22 Oct 1881., 1s.(2p.)
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. A.L.s. to Warren O. Fisher; Washington 16 Apr 1876., 1s.(4p.)
  *45M-181 (44). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. MS. telegram (recipient's copy) to Warren O. Fisher; Washington, 16 Apr 1876., 1s.(1p.)
  With this is a draft of Fisher's reply to Blaine, and 2 newspaper cuttings regarding the exchange.
  *45M-181 (45) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Blaine, James Gillespie, 1830-1893. A.L.s. to [William Wetmore] Story; Paris, 9 May 1888., 1s.(3p.)
  *41-2586. Purchased with the Friends fund from F.G. Sweet, 18 Oct 1941.
- Blair, Austin, 1818-1894. A. signature; Washington,[1867], 1s.(1p.)
- Blair, Montgomery, 1813-1883. Autograph. See Van Loan Album, p.75.
- Blake, Harrison Gray Otis. A.L.s.to James Thomas Fields; Worcester, 28 Feb 1881., 1s.(3p.)
- Blake, Sir Henry Arthur, 1840-1918. A.L.s.to [Sir Matthew?] Nathan; [London] 30 Jun 1911., 1s.(1p.)
- Blake, Lillie (Devereux) 1835-1913. A.L.s. to [Edmund Clarence] Stedman; Washington, 28 Mar 1862., 1s.(2p.)
- Blakeney, Edward Henry, 1869- A.L.s. to [Alfred Claghorn Potter]; Winchester, 21 Jun 1929., 1s. (2p.)
  *45M-646. Presented by Edward H. Blakeney, Esq., 8 July 1929.
- Blakeney, Edward Henry, 1869- A.L.s.(initials) to [William Francis] Prideaux; Ely [2 Jun 1914], 1s.(3p.)
- Blanc, Charles, 1813-1882. A.L.s. to [ ]; [Paris?] 28 Sep 1874., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (41). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Blanc, Charles, 1813-1882. A.L.s. to [Auguste Paul Charles] Anastasi; Paris, 7 Mar 1849., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (40). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Blanc, Louis, 1811-1882. A.L.s. to [ ]; Loudres, 19 Jan 1857., 1s.(1p.)
  in French.
  *42M-8. Purchased from H. P. Kraus, 13 July 1942.
- Blanc, Louis, 1811-1882. A.L.s. to Dr. [ ] Ashburne; London, 16 July 1849., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-499(10). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Blanc, Louis, 1811-1882. A.L.s. to [ ] Barney; [n.p.] 12 Jul 1853., 1s.(1p.)
  *48M-273. Presented by Mrs. Thomas Wentworth Higginson and Mrs. Margaret Higginson Barney, 1941.
- Blanc, Louis, 1811-1882. A.L.s. to [ ] Barrère; [London] 21 May 1862., 1s.(2p.) env.
  *55M-257 (9). Gift of Dr. E.B. Krumbhaar, 17 Nov 1955.
- Blanc, Louis, 1811-1882. A.L.s.to [ ] Trübner; Paris, 17 Apr 1895., 1s.(1p.)
  In French, with English translation.
- Blanchard, Jonathan, 1738-1788. A. receipt s.; Dunstable, 25 Mar 1782., 1s.(2p.)
- Blanchard, Joshua Pollard, 1782-1868. A.L.s.to Josiah Quincy; Boston, 23 Feb 1842., 1s.(2p.)
  Removed from Int 6201.8.
- Blaney, Aaron Roxbury, May 29, 1775
  Note for supplies signed by Griffin Greene Invoice of mollasses. Roxbury, December 15, 1775
  Supply order. Marblehead, May 27, 1775
  Note to Blaney signed by William Bowers.
- Blaney, Aaron Roxbury, May 6, 1776
  Note to Blaney from Robert Pope Undated account sheet. (several signatures of Thos. Clarke) Roxbury, June 19, 1775
  Note to Blaney from Moses Robbins Concord, May 29, 1775
  Note to Blaney from Jonos Heywood.
- Blaney, Aaron Roxbury, May 1775
  Military receipt for supplies. Roxbury, December 25, 1775
  Note to Mr. Walker signed by James Gardner. Account sheet for December 1776.
- Blaney, Aaron Camp near New York, September 22, 1776
  To A. Blaney from ? For another letter to Mr. Blaney see John Adams.
- Blatchford, Samuel, 1820-1893. 2 letters to Adam Badeau:
  - New York, 14 Mar 1884., 1s.(1p.) env.
  - Washington, 31 Dec 1887., 1s.(1p.)
- Bleecker, Harmanus, 1779-1849. Printed document, filled out in autograph and s.; Albany, 21 Oct 1800., 1s.(1p.)
- Blenner, Carle Joan. A.L.s.to [ ] Freiberger; New York, 23 Nov 1898., 1s.(3p.)
- Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of, 1789-1849. A.L. (in third person) to Skelton; Mackenzie; Kensington, 30 Apr 1838., 1s.(2p.)
  *45M-181(46) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of, 1789-1849. A.L.s. to [Lydia Howard (Huntley)] Sigourney; [London] 30 May 1845., 3s.(12p.)
  *45M-451 Gift of Prof. T.O. Mabbott, 24 Feb 1946.
- Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of, 1789-1849. A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 20 Sep 1845., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-499 (11). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Blessington, Charles John Gardiner, earl of, 1782-1829. A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 5 Aug 1825., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-499 (13). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Blessington, Marguerite (Power) Farmer Gardiner, countess of, 1789-1849. A.L. (3rd person) to Messrs. Ackerman; Anglesey, 6 Sep 1835., 1s.(2p.)
- Bliss, Richard, 1842-1920. 2 A.L.s.to E. W. Walker:
  - Newport, 9 Feb 1893., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 6 May 1893., 1s.(1p.)
- Bloch, Jean Richard, 1884-1947. A.L.s.to Harvard College Library; Poitiers (Vienne-France), 31 Dec 1914., 1s.(2p.)
  Interruption of L'Effort libre, during the war.
- Blodgett, William T. A.L.s.to Edmund Clarence Stedman; [New York] 8 Dec [ ]., 1s.(2p.)
- Blomefield, Leonard, originally Leonard Jenyns, 1800-1893. A.L.s. to Epes Sargent Dixwell; Newmarket, 28 Apr 1840., 1s.(3p.)
  *47M-373 (11). Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred M. Tozzer,; Mrs. Thomas Barbour, and Miss Gertrude A. Thurston, June 1943.
- Blomfield, Charles James, bp. of London, 1786-1857. A.L.s. ( C. J. London ) to [ ] bp. of Vermont; London, 8 Mar 1839., 1s.(3p.)
  Bequest of E. J. Wendell, 1918
- Blondin, Jean François Gravelet, called, 1824-1897. A.L.s. to [ ]; London, 14 Feb. 1862., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(47). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Blood, Thomas H. A.L.s. to John Locke; Sterling, 24 Jan 1825., 1s.(2p.)
- Bloomfield, Benjamin Bloomfield, 1st baron, 1768-1846. A.L.s.to [ ]; Carlter House, 30 Aug 1809., 1s.(2p.)
- Bloomfield, Joseph, 1753-1823. A.L.s. to Major Barker; Burlington, 3 Nov 1814., 1s.(2p.)
- Bloomfield, Robert, 1766-1823. A.L.s. to George [Bloomfield]; London, 21 Sep 1809., 1s.(4p.)
  Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, 31 Aug 1964.
- Bloomfield, Robert, 1766-1823. A.L.s. to [Mrs ] Palmer; [n.p.] 7 Dec [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  *50M-237. Purchased with the Bemis Fund, 17 Jan 1951.
- Blount, William, 1749-1800. 2 MS.D.s.; Knoxville, 1 and 10 Jul 1795. each, 1s.(2p.)
  Army pay orders. Blount was expelled from the U.S. Senate as a British agent in 1797.
  *54M-93. Presented by James N. B. Hill, Esq., 22 Oct 1954.
- Bludowsky, Ernest, baron. A.L.s. to Sir John Bowring; Tripolis, 15 Jun 1844., 1s.(4p.)
  Widener Library, Aug 1965.
- Blücher, Gebhard, Leberecht von, fürst von Wahlstadt, 1742-1819. A.L.s. to Gouvion Saint-Cyr; Rambouillet, 7 Aug 1815., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(48). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Blücher, Gebhard, Leberecht von, fürst von Wahlstadt, 1742-1819. MS.D.s.; [ ], 16 Jun 1808., 1s.(1p.)
- Blumenthal-Weiss, Ilse. Interview mit Ilse Blumenthal-Weiss anlaesslich des 25, Todestages des Dichters Rainer Maria Rilke. TS.(copy, unsigned); New York, 30 Dec 1951., 3s.(3p.)
  No source, 1954.
- Blunt, Wilfrid Scawen, 1840-1922. A.L.s.to Lady Georgiana Burne-Jones; [London ] 10 Mar 1909., 1s.(1p.)
- Blunt, Wilfrid Scawen, 1840-1922. A.MS. (unsigned); [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  Note written on f. 4v of To the marquess of Salisbury, k.g., [London, 1902]
  *66-1372. Gift of Amy Lowell, Jan 1967.
- Blussdorn, E. A.L.s.to Ben. W. Austin; Washington, [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Blyth, Sir Herbert William Blyth, 2d baron, 1868- T.L.s.to Sir Matthew Nathan; [London] 22 Feb 1911., 1s.(1p.)
- Blythe, Samuel George, 1868- Letters to Erastus Brainerd:
  - Washington, 15 Oct 1908., (1); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 1 Feb 1909., (2); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 24 Nov 1909., (3); 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 11 Mar 1910., (4); 1s.(1p.)
  - Ventnor, N.J., 20 Aug 1910., (5); 1s.(1p.)
  - Seattle, 2 Nov 1910., (6); 2s.(2p.)
  - Washington, 23 Feb 1914., (7); 1s.(1p.)
- Boaden, James, 1762-1839. A.L.s. to James Northcote; [London] 28 Aug 1827., 1s.(2p.)
  Contains Boaden's transcript of a poem ascribed to Alexander Pope, Verses on the Late Dean of Carlisle.
  *43M-107F 108F. Purchased with the Nichols fund from Elkin Mathews Ltd., 24 Aug-Sep 1943.
- Boardman, David Sherman, 1768-1864. Letters to Benson John Lossing:
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 16 Sep 1850., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 7 Jan 1851., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 15 Jan 1851., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 3 May 1851., 1s.(3p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 3 Jul 1851., 1s.(4p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 4 Feb 1852., 1s.(3p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 26 Apr 1852., 1s.(3p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 21 Jun 1852., 1s.(3p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 12 Jul 1852., 1s.(2p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 3 Sep 1852., 1s.(2p)
  - A.L.s.; New Milford, 3 Feb 1853., 1s.(4p)
- Boardman, Mabel Thorp. A.L.s.to [Dr ] Smith; Washington, 23 Apr 1913., 1s.(1p.)
- Bocock, John Paul. A.L.s.to Erastus Brainerd; Hampden, 29 Sep 1888., 1s.(2p.)
- Bodenstedt, Friedrich von, 1819-1892. A.L.s. to [ ]; Wiesbaden, 5 Jul 1878., 1s. (2p.)
  *70M-27. Gift of Carl F. Strauch, 21 Aug 1970.
- Bodini, Giovanni Battista, 1740-1813. A.L.s. to Michele Vincenzo Maria Malacarne; [n.p., n.d.], 1s. (2p.)
  Speaks of projected work on 100 roman and 100 exotic Fonts.
  *63M-13. Purchased with the Keller fund from Otto Haas, July 1963.
- Bogslau, B MS.L.s.to Trinity Historical Society of Dallas, Texas; Salsbourg, 8 Sep 1887., 1s.(1p.)
  Grand Duke of Toscane 's acceptance of honorary membership in the Society.
- Boileau, Sir John Peter, 1st bart., 1794-1869. A.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.] 3 Jun 1848., 1s.(1p.)
- Boileau-Despréaux, Nicolas, 1636-1711. A.L.s. (photostat) to Jean Racine; Auteuil, 6 Oct [1692], 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of J.H. Bertram, 28 June 1964.
- Boileau Despréaux, Nicolas, 1636-1711. ALs to [ ]; Auteuil (Paris, France), [ca. 1666] Oct. 6., 1s.(1p.)
  *96M-54. Gift of Joseph H. Bertram, 1997 June 13.
- Boisserée, Sulpiz, 1783-1854. A.L.s.to [ ]; Bonn, 21 Aug 1850., 1s.(2p.)
  Norton autographs, 1914.
- Boissier, Gaston, 1823-1908. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (42). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Boissy d'Anglas, Francois Antoine, baron, fl. 1905. A.L.s. to Robert Bacon; Paris, 21 Mar 1911., 1s.(1p.)
- Bok, Edward William, 1863-1930. ALs to Doris Houghton; Philadelphia (Pa.),1923 Mar., 1s.(1p.) env.
  *85M-45. Gift of Carl Seaburg, 1986 Apr. 23.
- Boker, George Henry, 1823-1890. A.L.s. to Adam Badeau; Philadelphia, 4 May 1887., 1s.(4p.)
- Bolingbroke, Henry St.John, 1st viscount, 1678-1751. [Additions and revisions to his Letters to a young nobleman on the study and use of history] A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p., 1745?], 2s.(5p.)
  Removed from *EC7.B6385.738L, which also contains autograph notes on end leaves.
  Purchased with the Child fund, 14 May 1946.
- Bolingbroke, Henry Saint-John, 1st viscount, 1678-1751. MS.D.s.; Windsor Castle, 24 Oct 1713., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181 (49). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bolles, James Aaron, 1810-1894. A.L.s.to Alfred Locke; [Boston] 10 Jul 1836., 1s.(1p.)
- Bolles, Ralph. MS.petition s. to Andrew Perkins; Norwich, Conn., 12 Dec 1798., 1s.(1p.)
- Bolton, Charles Powlett, 2d duke of, 1661-1722. A.L.s. to [James Craggs]; Chapel Lizard, 21 May 1719., 1s.(2p.)
  Concerns Joseph Addison.
  Recat. fr. MS Eng 4.
- Bonald, Louis Gabriel Ambroise, vicomte de, 1754-1840. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 1 Mar [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (43). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bonaparte, Charles Joseph, 1851-1921. Endorsed check; Boston, 31 Oct 1881., 1s.(1p.)
- Bonaparte, Charles Lucien, prince de Canino, 1803-1857. A.L.s. to [ ]; London, 21 Oct 1849., 1s.(1p.)
  *55M-257 (10). Gift of Dr. E.B. Krumbhaar, 17 Nov 1955.
- Bonaparte, Charles Lucien, Prince of Canino, 1803-1857. A.L.s. to [ ]; Philadelphia, 26 Dec 1824., 1s.(2p.)
- Bonaparte, Charles Lucien, prince de Canino, 1803-1857. MS.L.s. to [John] Cassin; Paris, 13 Jul 1857., 1s.(2p.)
  Transfer from MCZ.
- Bonaparte, Charlotte Napoléon (Bonaparte) 1802-1839. A.L.s. to [ ]; Marsden [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1374. Gift of W. B. O. Field, Winter 1942.
- Bonaparte, François Charles Joseph, Herzog von Reichstadt, called Napoleon II, 1811-1832. A.MS. (unsigned); [Vienna,1827], 1s.(2p.)
  Sheet from exercise book of compositions.
  *45M-181(50). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bonaparte, Jérôme Napoléon, 1832-1893. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 6 May 1862., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1408. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bonaparte, Jérôme Napoléon, 1805-1870. A.L.s. to Colonel [ ]; [ ] 11 Sep [ ], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1403. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bonaparte, Jérome Napoléon, 1805-1870. MS.L.s. to [ ] Maiors; Paris, 29 Dec 1849., 1s.(1p.)
  *55M-257 (11). Gift of Dr. E.B. Krumbhaar, 17 Nov 1955.
- Bonaparte, Napoléon Louis, prince, 1804-1831. MS.L.s. to [ ] General-Commandant La Lombardi; Milan [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bonaparte, Napoléon Louis, prince, 1804-1831. A.L.s.(facsimile) to [ ]; Paris [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bonaparte, Joseph Lucien Charles Napoléon, prince of Canino, 1824-1865. A.L.s. to Madame [ ] Mailland; Rome, 13 Nov 1850., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1719. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bonaparte, Jérôme Napoléon, 1805-1870. A.L.s.to William Patterson; Cambridge, 29 Mar 1826., 1s.(1p.)
  Gift of C. F. Gunther, 18 Mar 1890.
- Bonaparte, Lapagerie. MS.L.s.to [ ]; [n.p.] 25 Jul 1798., 1s.(1p.)
- Bonaparte, Lucien, prince of Canino, 1775-1840. A.D.s.; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1365. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bonaparte, Louis Lucien, prince, 1813-1891. 3 A.L.s. to Francisque Michel:
  - London, 3 May 1859., 1s. (3p.)
  - [N.p.] 7 Oct 1859., 1s. (1p.)
  - [N.p., n.d.], 1s. (1p.)
- Bonaparte, Napoléon Louis, prince, 1804-1831. A.L.s. to [Giuseppe Diazzi]; Rome, 20 Jul 1830., 1s.(1p.) cover.
  *42M-1716. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bonaparte, Napoléon Louis, prince, 1804-1831. A.L.s. to Marco Borini; Florence, 20 [ ] 1829., 1s.(3p.)
  *42M-1715. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bonaparte, Zenaide Charlotte Julie, 1801-1854. A.L.s. to Comte Graberg de Hemsoe; Rome, 17 May 1845., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1372. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- [ Bonaparte family ] 6 letters. Attributed to members of the Bonaparte family.
  *42M-1725. Gift of W. B. O. Field, winter 1942.
- Bonaparte family, subject. Tombs of the Bonapartes: manuscript list; no place, undated.
  In unidentified hand.
  No accession number. Gift of Charles H. Taylor, Boston; received: 1924 December 6. [Found with: MS Storage 281. Collection materials assembled by Carolyn Jakeman].
- Bond, Elizabeth L. 2 A.L.s. to Helen E. Marshall:
  - Cambridge, 20 Jul [ca. 1932], 3s. (5p.)
  - same, 25 Jul [ca. 1932], 1s. (3p.)
    *69M-109. Gift of Helen E. Marshall, 23 Jan 1970.
- Bond, George, 1788-1842. [Account of the illness and death of his daughter Ann] A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p.] 1828., 11f. (20p.)
- Bond, Louisa (Greenwood) 1810- A.L.s. to [Abigail (May)] Alcott; Middlebury, 1 Feb 1843., 1s.(4p.)
  *81M-64. Purchased with the P.D. Howe fund, June 1982.
- Bond, William Cranch, 1789-1859. A.L.s.to William Bond and Son; New York, 19 Apr 1833., 1s.(2p.)
  Harvard Archives, 8 Feb 1939.
- Bonet-Maury, Gaston, 1842-1919. A.L.s.to [ ]; Paris, 18 Jan 1895., 1s.(4p.)
- Bonner, Paul Hyde, 1893- A.L.s.to Mary V. Elzemeyer; Summerville, 9 Sep [1959], 1s.(2p.) postcard.
  *60M-67. Gift of Miss Rena C. Harrell, Oct 1960.
- Bonner, Paul Hyde, 1893- A.L.s. to Mary V. Elzemeyer; Summerville, 30 Apr 1962., 1s.(1p.) env.
  *62M-300. Gift of Miss Rena C. Harrell, 1 June 1963.
- Bonner, Paul Hyde, 1893- A.L.s. to Rena C. Harrell; Summerville, 6 May, 1962.
  *62M-301 Gift of Miss Rena C. Harrell, 1 June 1963.
- Bonner, Robert, 1824-1899. A.L.s. to Fitz-Greene Halleck; New York 7 Nov 1862., 1s.(1p.)
  *54M-156. Presented by Miss Eleanor M. Tilton, 11 Aug 1954.
- Bonner, Robert, 1824-1899. 2 A.L.s.to Charles Nordhoff:
  - New York, Aug 1869., 1s.(1p.)
  - Same, 15 Oct 1869., 1s.(1p.)
- Bonney, Thomas George, 1833-1923. A.L.s.to [ ]; [London] 2 Oct 1903., 1s.(4p.)
  Gratis, 1956.
- Boojum's adventure. Ms; [n.p.], 1879 Feb. 20., 3s.(10p.)
  Autobiographical tale of a dog. Attributed to Henry Adams, 1838-1918 in repository file note.
  *93M-99. Gift of Ephraim Whitman Gurney, 1892 May 22.
- [Booksellers' inventory] MS. (unidentified hand); [London, ca. 1640], 1s.(2p.)
  *76M-62. Gift of Theodore Hofmann, Nov 1976.
- Boone, Daniel, 1734-1820. A.L.s. to Judge Caleren; [n.p.] 5 Oct 1809., 1s.(1p.)
  Facsimile.
  *45M-181(53). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Boone, Daniel, 1734-1820. A.L.s. to [G] [C]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(52,54). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Booth, Edwin, 1833-1893. A.L.s. to Miss [ ] Blatchford; Boston, 10 May 1877., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1942. Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Booth, Edwin, 1833-1893. A.L.s. to Miss [ ] Blatchford; [Boston] 22 Nov [1880?], 1s.(2p.) env.
  *42M-1941 (23). Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Booth, Edwin, 1833-1893. Autograph signature. Boston, Apr 1871., 1s.(1p.)
  *42M-1941 (22). Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Thomas Barbour and others, June 1942.
- Booth, Edwin, 1833-1893, subject. Sargent's portrait of Edwin Booth at the Players: photograph of portrait, 1890 June., 1 folder.
  Includes an autograph manuscript poem (signed) by Thomas Bailey Aldrich.
  42M-1136. Gift of Talbot Aldrich; received: 1942 June 7.
- Booth, Evangeline, 1865- A.L.s.to George Becks; Poughkeepsie, 10 Mar 1886., 1s.(2p.)
- Booth, Franklin, 1874- Letters to E. W. Walker Company:
  - A.L.s.; Cambridge, 3 May 1893., (1); 1s.(1p.) postcard.
  - A.L.s.; same, 5 May 1893., (2); 1s.(1p.) postcard
  - A.L.s.;same,13 May [1893?], (3); 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.;same,20 Dec [1893?], (4); 1s.(2p.)
- Booth, William, 1829-1912. T.L.(facsimile signature) to [ ]; London, Feb 1912., 1s.(1p.)
  *60M-136. Presented by Mr. Mrs. J. F. Fleming, Dec 1960.
- Booth, William, 1829-1912. A.signature; Montreal, Canada, 18 Oct 1902.
- Borchardt, Rudolf, 1877-1945. T.L.s. to Werner Jaeger; [n.p., n.d.], 4s.(4p.)
- Booth, Junius Brutus, 1796-1852. A.theatre pass, s.; [Boston, n.d.]
  Gift of Mrs. Murray A.Potter, 1 July 1930.
- Booth, Junius Brutus, 1796-1852. A.L.s. to John Pritt Harley; [London] 7 Feb 1837., 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-1121. Gift of Talbot Aldrich, 7 June 1943.
- Booth, Junius Brutus, 1796-1852. A.L.s. to [ ]; [Louisville] 4 Jan. 1834., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(56). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Booth, Junius Brutus, 1796-1852. A.L.s. to [ ]; Louisville, 13 Jan 1834., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(55). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Borcke, Heros von, 1835-1895. A.L.s.to [ ]; Giesenbrügge, 21 Mar 1882., 1s.(4p.)